[ DIVINE 'S " GOOD AND PLENTY " PLAYING OVER SPEAKERS ]
[ WOMAN CHUCKLES ]
That I 'm the one That 's gonna show you love
I 'll give you good and plenty of it
So beautiful .
[ RUMBLING ]
WOMAN 1 : What 's that ?
- Did you feel something ? - Yeah , I feel something .
Shh . Heh , heh .
MAN : Hey , get back here !
WOMAN 2 : Whoo ! Turn up the music !
Oh , yeah
We 're having a party , man .
Yeah , you guys are having fun . Boat 's rocking .
[ RUMBLING ]
- Shh , shh . - Shh . Whoa , heh , heh .
WOMAN 2 : Stop !
MAN : You 're paranoid ! WOMAN 2 : Listen .
[ RUMBLING ]
Yeah . Okay .
Did you hear that ?
Listen , listen .
MAN : You hear that ? - What 's that ?
Everybody , shh . Shh .
Stay up there .
What is that ?
[ SCREAMING ]
WOMAN : Come on !
[ GUNSHOT ]
Okay , we 've had some problems at the facility .
What we 're attempting to achieve has never been done .
We 're this close to the reactivation of a human brain cell .
The 200 million I 've given this company is due in great part to your research .
But when the market opens Monday
despite my reputation , I don 't like heights .
Especially falling from them .
I 'm sorry , honestly .
Tell me , Mr. Franklin , have you ever known anyone with Alzheimer 's ?
Well , no .
By the end , all my father could do was ask why my mother wasn 't at home .
Each time I said she was dead , I watched him take the loss like a car wreck .
200,000 men and women develop Alzheimer 's each year .
What if you could end all that suffering with a single pill ?
Give me till Monday morning . Forty-eight hours .
My results will skyrocket your stock price
or I 'll help you pack the lab myself .
It 's your call .
That was an impressive speech you gave back there .
SUSAN : I read that article on you .
- The thing in the Himalayas . - Alps .
Right .
We were just trying to do something together .
Having fun .
Things went bad .
But you saved all those people .
Not all .
SUSAN : Navy built it for WWll submarine loading
refueling .
When they mothballed it , we picked it up , added aquatic pens , underwater labs .
Your dime , I guess .
Looks like Alcatraz floats .
[ WORKER CARTER SPEAKING IN SPANISH ]
What do you think ? She 's a 12-footer . She 's beautiful .
- She wants to give you a big kiss . - I bet .
She 's got a license plate jammed in her mouth .
It 's a good deal , amigo .
[ SPEAKS IN SPANISH ]
Drop her , Billy !
Russell Franklin , Janice Higgins .
Marine biologist .
Jan will get you settled .
Welcome to our island paradise .
Where 's Tattoo ?
You know , short guy ?
[ IN FRENCH ACCENT ] " The plane , boss ! The plane ! "
Right .
[ IN NORMAL VOICE ] I am getting old .
How much do you know about our facility ?
Treat me like a tourist .
I hate tourists and I 've decided I like you .
[ LOCK BEEPS ]
Hey !
" Louisiana . "
Probably bought in a pet shop in Baton Rouge .
Ate everything in his tank , and then the guy that bought him .
Next day , fills up the cab of the guy 's truck with water and drives to Baja
picking bones out of his teeth with the license plate .
We need to talk .
Later .
Carter Blake , Russell Franklin , president of Chimera Pharmaceuticals .
Whoa .
That was incredible .
Actually , they don 't like the taste of us very much .
They bite you , it 's because they think you 're a fat little seal .
Or a rich suit .
Nice meeting you .
Friendly place .
You got full sentences . Usually , he just kind of nods .
Word travels fast about why you 're here and all .
Was that the Gen One that escaped ?
That little guy ? No way . Those are the normals .
These are the test sharks .
Two first-generation and one second-generation female .
Beneath its glassy surface
a world of gliding monsters .
It 's pretty scary stuff , huh ?
Yes . It is .
WOMAN [ OVER PA ] : Tower to water taxi . Tower to water taxi .
Ben , I 'm picking up a nasty little bitch of a squall about 30 miles out . Over .
MAN [ OVER RADIO ] : Copy that . We 'll be all right .
[ JOHNNY NASH 'S " I CAN SEE CLEARLY NOW " PLAYING ]
I can see clearly now
Jan , stay out of the rain .
Where are they going ? They hate me too ?
Oh . They 're going home . We run a skeleton crew on the weekend .
But they probably hate you anyway .
There 's Dr. Jim Whitlock , the most brilliant man ever .
He 's pissing into the wind . How brilliant can he be ?
You 'll see .
- It 's gonna be a bright - Bright
- Bright - Bright sunshine-y day
TOM : What happened ? You miss with the first shot ?
It took two hits to even slow it down .
Are you kidding ? Two of these things should 've killed it .
Tell it that , Scoggs .
You missed . Don 't get mad at me because you can 't shoot worth a shit .
If you hadn 't left the pen open , I could 've got a good night 's sleep .
I already told the doc , I locked the pen like I do every other night .
- The fish got out some other way . - Huh .
Huh .
What are you looking at me like that for ? Who you gonna trust ?
Me , that 's who . You trust me .
You know why ? Because I 'm trustworthy .
How high are these fences off the water ?
Given the surface variations and tensile strength ...
Scoggs . Short answer , man .
Eight feet , give or take a centimeter .
JANICE : I 'm sorry . I 'm making Aquatica sound like a mental hospital .
FRANKLIN : No , not really .
Well , heh , heh , maybe a little .
The truth is , it is .
But almost everyone here is top of their game .
Living below is like living in space . You don 't get very many mistakes .
Besides the catwalks
you bought us titanium-based fencing around all the lagoon and pens .
There are three sub-levels . Sub-level One is living quarters .
Two : Wet lab and workshops .
And Three : Engineering and air-locked wet entry .
Welcome to Aquatica .
[ RUMBLING ]
Did you dose the Gen Two with the serum ?
I had Carter do it after you called . It should be ready tomorrow night .
- But ? - We will not be ready .
Two months ahead of schedule .
We 're skipping three rounds of preliminary trials .
SUSAN : No choice .
You wait your whole life for a single moment
and then one day , it 's tomorrow .
FRANKLIN : So what exactly does a shark wrangler do ?
CARTER : Pretty much what it sounds like , I guess .
How 'd you end up here at Aquatica ?
CARTER : I like the water .
Pay 's good .
Hey , an AGA mask . Did some wreck diving in one of these , off the coast of Spain .
Tourist thing .
CARTER : Mm-hm .
Do you like wreck diving ?
It 's okay .
I bet you 're good at it .
We 're on the water . Whole cat-and-mouse thing don 't float .
- You 're the man , right ? - Yeah .
Yeah , I 'm the man .
The man 's always got a file . What 's it say ?
Two years , Leavenworth . Smuggling .
How 'd you make your money ?
You the first rich guy in history who 's squeaky-clean ?
You do understand my concern , right ?
Look , I got a workable deal here .
I don 't make waves .
I meet the terms of my parole .
I 'm not out to change the world , like the doc .
I 'm not out to wreck it either .
[ OVER SPEAKERS ] Money , money make the world go round
WOMAN 'S VOICE : Eat me , asshole !
In and out of town Rolling over here
Hey , you dickhead !
Now , what you hear is what you get
coming from the kingpins In the wild , wild West
[ PARROT SQUAWKS ]
PARROT : Fat butt !
You got a big fat butt .
You know what , bird ?
You 're trying my last nerve . Don 't make me drown your feathery ass .
Get myself a cat .
That 's good . Yes . That 's good .
Mm .
That 's it .
You got a nasty-looking tongue , you know that ?
Talking ' bout Talking ' bout money
[ METAL CREAKING AND RUMBLING ]
Feeding time .
TOM [ OVER RADIO ] : I 'm releasing the tiger shark in 30 seconds . Copy .
CARTER : I hear you . I 'm going in .
You guys hungry ?
Dr. McAlester , we have a situation up here .
Could you please come to surface level ?
[ OVER RADIO ] Dr. McAlester , could you come to surface level , please ?
Hello ?
[ GUNSHOT ]
Surprise !
Happy birthday !
[ LAUGHING ]
[ OVER SPEAKERS ] Gold , pearls and diamond rings
All expensive , shinin ' things
Damn , I hate that song .
You like the tunes there , Preach ?
And when the cash don 't shine
They close their eyes for life
Carter , join us . There 's too much woman on this deck for Scoggs to handle .
FRANKLIN : Vodka , straight .
And by the way , food was excellent , brother .
You 're that guy that got caught in that avalanche , right ?
Yeah . I 'm the one .
Black men have enough ways to get killed
without climbing up some mountain in the middle of nowhere .
You need to leave that to the white folks , " brother . "
Happy birthday ?
I 'll let you know tomorrow .
How 's life underwater ?
Well , it 's a lot less complicated
than it is on the surface .
That 's for sure .
Nice work with that new tiger shark today .
You 'll have to tell me how you learned that .
One day , you 'll take me up on that beer and maybe I will .
It 's all work for me , Carter .
But , like you said , " one day . "
Sharks never get cancer , go blind or show loss of brain activity as they age .
Unlike some people I know .
Sharks are the oldest creatures on the planet
from a time when the world was just flesh and teeth .
JANICE : By using a hormonal enhancer
we increased this female 's forebrain to five times its normal size .
To harvest more protein .
Exactly . A protein that may reactivate ...
That will .
- That will reactivate human brain cells stored in the forebrain of the shark .
I 'm just amazed that we 've come so far , so fast , without genetic tampering .
Genetic engineering to increase brain mass violates the Harvard Compact .
Not to mention Chimera policy .
They 're hunting in packs .
Like wild dogs .
They 'll only eat other sharks .
You 're reading too much into it .
That Gen One attacked a 25-foot boat .
Am I reading too much into that too ?
Did you tell Franklin ?
I 'm just a fish keeper , lady .
But bringing in that shark ahead of schedule was a very bad idea .
Do you like your job ?
Are you threatening me , doc ?
No .
But if we don 't pull off that test tomorrow , we 're all on the street .
You 're a good man , Carter .
But with your background ...
Ah .
Right .
How 's Miss Smarty-Pants ?
Hope she 's not as dumb as she seems .
Raise those fences like I asked ?
I took care of it . Let 's go get a beer .
[ THUNDER CRASHES ]
MAN [ OVER RADIO ] : U.S. Coast Guard advisories include :
All craft warnings for waters south of the U.S. Mainland and west of cA .
A tropical depression is generating gale-force winds
and is associated with heavy rains and ocean swells to 30 feet or more .
Repeat : U.S. Coast Guard advisories ...
[ OVER SPEAKERS ] With the writing on the wall
[ PARROT SQUAWKS ]
Any of your nonsense , and we 'll have tiny drumsticks on the menu tonight .
Fat butt !
PREACH : That 's right .
You can ... all you want .
Welcome to my parlor , Mr. Franklin .
Wow .
Wet lab , we 're taking a pounding up here . Can 't see past my nose .
[ OVER RADIO ] So I suggest you check pen monitors and lagoon monitors .
I can 't imagine there 's much visibility below .
Carter , you copy ?
Carter ?
CARTER [ OVER RADIO ] : Okay , I 'm approaching the tunnel .
TOM : Bingo . Elvis has left the building .
We picked you up , but visibility 's near zero .
CARTER : No problem .
How long have they been synchronized like this ?
Tell me I didn 't see that .
They recognized that gun !
That 's impossible . Sharks can 't swim backwards !
- Try to stay focused . TOM : What was that ?
We lost picture in Gen Two pen .
Okay , hold on .
Carter , do you copy ?
TOM : Carter , talk to me , man . Do you copy ?
Cut the crap ! You 're scaring everybody .
Carter !
TOM : Boarding platform engaged .
He 's got her .
Did someone order the fish ?
What in God 's creation ?
No , not his .
Ours .
Commencing scan .
Gen Two is online . Transferring exotics to remote terminals .
Vital signs to terminal one .
Diagnostic imaging to terminal two .
We 're live and in color !
JANICE : BP , 67 over 43 .
Heart rate , 50 B.P.M. Within norms .
She 's sleeping like a baby .
Okay .
Bad dreams ?
In position .
Vitals are stable .
Vitals ?
- Holding . - Aspirating 4.5 cc 's .
Introducing 2 cc 's of the protein complex
into cultured , inactive brain neurons of an Alzheimer 's patient .
And what you 're looking for here is lightning in a bottle .
Protein complex is interacting with the neurons .
Neurons are becoming hyperosmotic .
Membrane integrity 's improving .
They 're firing !
- They 're firing ! - One second .
Two . Three .
- Still firing . - Four . Five . Six .
6.560 seconds .
I 'll be damned .
No , sir . For 6.560 seconds
you saw what it 's like not to be damned .
Ha , ha , ha . Congratulations .
SUSAN : Lmpressed ? FRANKLIN : Overly impressed .
SUSAN : 6.560 seconds .
FRANKLIN : Now that you 've got this
how long before you make something permanent ?
JIM : You did it , pal .
You did it .
[ JIM SCREAMS ]
No !
Jim !
Carter , no !
[ ALARM WAILING ]
Are you insane ?
Tower , we need paramedics and evac now !
BRENDA : All frequencies , SOS .
[ OVER RADIO ] This is Research Station Aquatica .
We have a medical emergency . I repeat :
This is Research Station Aquatica . We have a medical emergency .
Please respond .
X-ray Alpha 2-18 .
Coming off oil platform Chiapa .
We 'll take that post you 've always wanted .
SUSAN : Got it .
He 's hemorrhaging !
JANICE : They say the yellow butterflies are thick as clouds there , remember ?
MAN [ OVER RADIO ] : Research Station Aquatica , this is X-ray Alpha 2-18 .
Have you in sight . Approaching from 0-6-0 .
Copy , 2-18 .
Stay with him . Keep talking .
Let 's move !
I 'm not this kind of doctor .
FRANKLIN : Just keep doing what you 're doing .
Where 's the chopper ? Tower ?
Come on , Brenda . Where 's my chopper ?
CARTER : Franklin , this end !
[ SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY ]
Keep it coming !
Ready . It 's all right , honey . Hold on .
CARTER : Got it . Okay , move him out .
- Let 's go ! Let 's go ! - Go !
One ! Two ! Three !
[ SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY ]
I love you !
[ JANICE SCREAMS ]
- Come on ! - Get up ! Come on !
- Carter ! - Carter !
Come on , Carter ! Come on !
[ WHIRRING AND SQUEALING ]
[ SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY ]
Arriba ! Pull up , 2-18 ! Pull up !
Damn ! I can 't get a picture .
Tower , have you got a visual ? Copy .
TOM : I can 't get anything .
- Do you copy ? TOM : Going to backup .
Got it !
[ SCREAMING ]
[ SCREAMS ]
I 'm gonna take this as a sign .
Where is he now ?
Where is he ?
- The whole system 's shut down . - Brenda ?
Are you there ?
TOM : This thing is dead .
FRANKLIN : Somebody , please
tell me what that is .
Please .
All right , people , let 's move .
Now !
Get to the door !
You can 't help him .
[ CRYING ]
Let 's go . Go ! Go !
Go ! Go !
Go !
SUSAN : Carter !
JANICE : Let 's go ! - Come on !
TOM : The door frame is bent .
[ GRUNTS ]
SUSAN : Come on , Scoggs ! - Open it !
SUSAN : Come on , go , go , go !
FRANKLIN : Go !
TOM : Turn it ! Turn it !
No !
Brenda ?
Tower , can you hear me ?
Anyone , hello ?
[ METAL CREAKING ]
We gotta get topside , find help .
- What ? - We 're flooded .
FRANKLIN : Oh , shit !
There 's no other stairway from this level .
Elevator ?
It seals off automatically to keep the shaft from filling .
There 's no way up .
All right , all right , okay , okay .
If this is a lesson about the drinking , let 's just say I 've learned it .
No need to get carried away , showing me your vengeful side .
I know your wrath , Lord .
CARTER : If corridor B is dry
we go back to the maintenance ladder , climb down to level three .
We get to the wet entry .
We take the sub topside , two at a time . We go down to get up .
All right , let 's move . Come on .
[ CRASH THEN RUMBLING ]
[ PREACH SCREAMING ]
Shit !
[ THUD ]
Sounds like somebody made it .
TOM : Over here ! We 're over here !
[ THUDDING ]
Whoa , whoa , whoa .
Preach ?
What the hell is that ?
Lab equipment maybe , banging around .
- Think so ? - Not a chance .
We gotta get past that door .
Let 's do it !
Come on !
CARTER : Give me a hand !
Open the door !
Go ! Go !
PREACH : Bird !
Come on , bird !
Where are you , bird ?
PARROT : Hey , dickhead !
PREACH : Bird ?
Fat butt !
Bird ?
Anybody here ?
Cowboy , let me ask you a question .
- We should keep moving . - I 'm talking to him !
Was that a goddamn shark broke through that door ?
- I expect so . - You expect so ?
Huh . Well , well , well .
Am I the only asshole down here who thinks that a tad bit odd ?
It can do that ? Bust through a steel door ?
I ain 't the expert .
Given Gen Two 's size and some room to move
she could put a couple tons , maybe more , into a hit .
So , yeah , in my opinion .
If she wants through , she 's coming .
And these sharks
they aren 't breaking down doors for the sheer joy of it , are they ?
They 're after us .
It 's obvious we don 't know what they 're doing .
What the hell did you do to those sharks ?
Their brains weren 't large enough for sufficient amounts of the protein .
So we violated the Harvard Compact .
Jim and I used gene therapies to increase their brain mass .
Larger brain means more protein .
As a side effect , the sharks got smarter .
You stupid bitch !
[ CRYING ]
I didn 't want this to happen
but with this research , we could wipe out degenerative brain disease .
Think of the generations that would be saved .
How much dynamite do you have to set off in your ears before your head clears ?
You wouldn 't understand .
I wouldn 't , huh ?
Dumb old Carter wouldn 't understand that you used us ?
That you used me ?
Someone on the water who wouldn 't make waves .
Someone who wouldn 't ask too many questions .
Because he had something to lose .
You don 't see what we 've done here .
You 've taken God 's oldest killing machine and given it a will .
You 've knocked us to the bottom of the goddamn food chain .
It 's not a great leap forward , in my book .
People we 'll save ...
Jim ? Brenda ?
Us ?
FRANKLIN : All right , people .
These sharks are thinking hard and clear .
So here 's the riddle .
What does an 8000-pound mako shark
with a brain the size of a V-8 engine and no natural predators , think about ?
I 'm not waiting around here to find out .
Now you see how that works ?
She screwed with the sharks and now the sharks are screwing with us .
[ PANTING ]
Please let me get out of here .
[ YELLS ]
[ SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY ]
What if the sharks get through the fence and into the ocean ?
It 's okay . The fence on the ocean side is titanium .
And it gives , so it works just like a net .
CARTER : Let 's get to the sub . We 'll discuss it on the way to the top .
[ SQUAWKING ]
PARROT : Eat me , asshole .
Careful , now .
Come on , bird . Come on .
[ CLUCKING ]
- Please , baby . - Dickhead .
See Daddy smiling ?
Come on . Bring your feathery ass here . Come on .
[ SCREAMS ]
[ SCREAMING ]
[ GASPING ]
- Explosion caused that ? - No .
Nothing in here could 've blown with enough force to move that damn sub .
Whatever . It 's junk .
We could all just dive in and see who makes it to the top .
Isn 't that the old Aquatica spirit , Dr. Susie ?
Just dive in .
You could go first , just to lead by example .
He was my best friend , Janice .
I 'm not going in the water .
- No way , man ! The sharks are in there . - Listen !
We put these on . They help fight hypothermia . That 's a start .
And unless someone 's got a better idea
we 're going to have to swim out of here .
[ GAS HISSING ]
This isn 't happening .
[ COUGHING ]
I 'm not Daniel when he faced the lion !
So I appreciate the irony , Lord !
" Cook dies in his own oven ! "
But I 've got other plans !
[ GASPS ]
You ate my bird .
Was that the surface ?
The vibrations are too deep . That was from inside .
CARTER : I wouldn 't get that close .
Just a suggestion .
Water 's murky . We might make it .
No way ! No , we won 't !
It 's 230 feet
from the lagoon floor to the lagoon surface !
The average human swims two feet per second .
The average shark swims 50 feet per second .
There 's no way I 'm getting into that pool !
What we have here is your basic maintenance ladder .
This leads up to the surface .
I love you , Scoggs . I really do !
Why do I feel a " but " coming on ?
But we don 't know what shape the surface is in .
This shaft is air-locked .
But if the explosion breached the shaft at surface level
we won 't have enough pressure to stabilize the pool .
If the pool isn 't stabilized , there 's tons of ocean dying to get in .
You 'll bring the whole facility down .
We 're better off with the sharks .
You wanna swim with your fishes ? Go ahead !
I 'm opening this door and climbing out of here !
- The hell you are ! - I don 't work for you anymore !
- I don 't take orders ! - Enough !
That 's enough now , from all of you !
You think water 's fast ?
You should see ice . It moves like it has a mind .
Like it knows it killed the world once . It got a taste for murder .
When the avalanche came
it took us a week to climb out .
And somewhere , we lost hope .
I don 't know when we turned on each other .
I just know
that seven of us survived the slide
and only five made it out .
Now , we took an oath that I 'm breaking now .
Swore that we 'd say it was the snow that killed the other two .
But it wasn 't .
Nature can be lethal .
But it doesn 't hold a candle to man .
You 've seen how bad things can get and how quick they can get that way .
Well , they can get a whole lot worse .
So we 're not going to fight anymore !
We 're going to pull together and find a way to get out of here !
First , we 're gonna seal off this pool !
[ JANICE SCREAMING ]
[ FRANKLIN SCREAMS ]
Oh , my God .
It just ate him .
It just ate him . Christ !
I 'm not moving .
I 'm not moving . Someone will come .
They 'll come and they 'll get us , and we 'll be fine .
- Scoggs . - No . I 'm not moving .
Listen , Tom , what is the precise structural failure limit for Aquatica ?
3200 tons .
What happens when we get more than 3200 tons of water in this rig ?
The support struts go first . Their tolerance is about seven tons .
They 'll crack like toothpicks .
The walls will buckle . They can 't handle more than 10 tons of pressure .
You wanna be here for that ?
Hell , no . Hell , no .
The moment of truth . Again .
Go ! Go ! Go !
Tom !
I got you .
JANICE : Aah ! TOM : It 's burning !
The elevator 's blocking the top .
If we make it to level one , we can take the stairs out .
[ THUDDING ]
Let 's get out of here !
Go ! Go ! Go !
What are you doing ?
If they break through , water will bring them right to us .
Level two 's only partially flooded . If I can get that door open
the water will run off there , buy us some time .
You 're big , real big .
- What 's that ? - The size of your brass balls .
Be careful .
CARTER : Go !
Go !
Go , go !
Carter !
[ SCREAMING ]
Jan !
Jan , stay there !
JAN : Carter !
Carter !
Get me out of here , Carter !
I don 't wanna die !
Grab my hand ! Come on !
Come on !
I can 't ! I can 't reach !
- Aah ! Can 't reach ! - Take it !
[ SCREAMING ]
[ SOBBING ]
- Scoggs . TOM : Yeah ?
Can you reach that door above you ?
It 's too high .
[ THUDDING ]
Sharks probably flooded that level too .
[ METAL THUDDING THEN CREAKING ]
Good thing you came to this side . The other side 's under water .
- We didn 't exactly plan it . - Yeah , it wasn 't planned .
Are you all that made it ?
TOM : We did it .
We 're on level one . We can take the stairs to the surface .
The stairs are flooded . Trust me , I know .
Are you sure ?
Give us a goddamn break , can 't you ?
[ RUMBLING ]
He always answers .
Sometimes , the answer you get isn 't the answer you want .
We 're 60 feet from the surface .
There 's an emergency hatch on this level , right ?
This level has bilge pumps on it for storm runoff .
If we re-route the emergency generators , we could drain a stairway .
- You sure ? - Who you gonna trust ?
- You . - That 's right .
You trust me .
You know , we had poker here tomorrow night .
She 'd draw to the inside straight when she could 've stuck with a pair .
Big dreams .
Even in death : Standards .
Okay , Jan was a healthy girl .
Something in here has to run on batteries .
- Nice . TOM : Where would a girl keep her
mm , thing ? - What 's the matter with you ?
My skin 's starting to hemorrhage .
The sharks smell the blood ...
This 'll coat it with oil .
Look , Carter , what you said down there ...
Maybe you were right .
Everything I 've done
I don 't think I could 've done it without you .
I know , Susan . That 's the problem .
PREACH : Four a.m.
I know . One night feels like a whole week .
- Relativity . - What ?
Einstein 's theory of relativity .
Grab hold of a hot pan , a second can seem like an hour .
Put your hands on a hot woman
an hour can seem like a second .
It 's all relative .
I spent four years at Cal Tech . That 's the best physics explanation I 've heard .
[ CHUCKLES ]
It works .
You stay with the doc .
Me and Scoggs are gonna try to get to the wet lab
drain that stairwell .
- Preach ? - What ?
Would you zip me up , please ?
TOM : We got one , there 's two sharks left
and you and the doc are doing a little bathroom love .
They got a pill for what 's wrong with you ?
I need to get some things from my quarters . Research data .
The tests , they worked .
So much death around us , to risk any more life for some numbers ...
Without that data , everyone dying isn 't just tragic , it 's useless .
Death is always useless , doctor .
This is it .
I 'll be back before you know it .
Carter !
[ SCREAMING ]
What 's going on ? !
What the fuck 's going on ? What is that ?
- It 's okay ! - Okay !
- What is that ? - We 're all right !
- What the fuck ? ! - It 's okay . It 's okay . It 's okay .
I thought you were coming back for me .
One of your monitors is blocking the panel .
- You wanna help me move it ? - Yeah .
I say we do everything right together .
Right together .
Hello .
My name is Sherman Dudley
and if this message finds you , I did not survive , so this is my legacy .
I have loved the pulpit , and I have loved the bottle .
I did my best to be a good husband , a father .
I came up wanting .
So what do I have to say to you ?
What mark do I have to leave behind ?
We 'll begin with the perfect omelet , made with two eggs , not three .
Amateurs often add milk for density . This is a mistake .
Carter !
Come on !
[ GLASS BREAKS ]
PREACH : I got you . Come on .
Damn it , Scoggs .
Where 's Susan ?
PREACH : I 'm done .
Brothers never make it out of situations like this . Not ever !
[ SCREAMS ]
[ GASPING ]
[ SCREAMING ]
CARTER : Susan !
Susan ! Susan !
Did you do it ? Where 's Scoggins ?
I hate to interrupt this moment of burgeoning intimacy
but can we get the fuck out of here ?
- Is this the only way ? - Exits are flooded .
Whole place is sinking . It 's this way or no way at all .
You can bring on the good news anytime now .
Sharks are attracted to churning water , bright colors .
The extinguishers will be a distraction .
What about us ?
The vest 'll bring you up too fast . Your lungs 'll pop like a balloon .
You weren 't the sunny kid in your class .
I never went to class .
How far to the surface ? Sixty feet ?
There 's nothing to it . Exhale on the way up , and get the hell out of the water .
I gotta equalize the pressure before we blow the air lock .
I gotta let the room fill up with water .
It 'll only take a few seconds .
You ready ?
- No . - Not in the least .
Though I walk through the valley of the shadow of death
I shall fear no evil
for thou art with me .
Thy rod and thy staff , they comfort me .
Surely goodness and mercy shall follow me all the days of my life
because I carry a big stick
and I 'm the meanest motherfucker in the valley .
Two sharks down , Lord . One demon fish to go .
Can I get an amen ?
SUSAN : Amen . CARTER : Amen .
PREACH : I can 't hear you ! SUSAN CARTER : Amen !
PREACH : Give me an amen !
Stay with us , Lord !
Okay , hold on three ! Ready ?
One ! Two ! Three !
[ GRUNTS ]
[ SCREAMING ]
Swim !
Oh , my God !
It 's the devil , you know .
He 'll be okay if we can get out of here .
Son of a bitch .
What ?
Those fences are titanium underneath
but on top , they 're just plain steel .
They 've been herding us , pushing us where they want .
Using us to flood the facility .
Oh , my God .
That 's the answer to the riddle .
Because that 's what an 8000-pound mako thinks about .
About freedom .
About the deep blue sea .
We have to kill her .
That 's the first real smart thing you 've said all day .
[ METAL CRASHES ]
Here we go .
Let 's go .
We ought to get 21 / 2 sticks of dynamite out of these flares .
From up here , you ought to be able to see me spear it .
When I do , you take this end of this cable
hook it up to the boat battery .
And boom !
Damn ! I can 't get her !
She 's too far away !
I know how to get her .
How ?
- Bait . - What ?
She may be the smartest animal in the world
but she 's still just an animal .
Come to Mama .
No ! Susan !
No !
Susan , don 't !
Get out of the water !
All right , Lord ...
CARTER : Shoot it , Preach !
- This is for Scoggins . - Shoot it !
[ SCREAMING ]
Damn !
CARTER : Blow it , Preach ! Blow it !
The battery !
Blow it !
Do it !
Yeah !
Carter !
Hey !
Bring me some sushi !
Forty-five-foot shark
and you hit me .
Nice .
Could 've been worse . I could 've let him eat your ass .
Carter , we 're sinking , right ?
Yeah .
Let me ask you something .
Are you sure it was just three sharks ?
Yeah .
Oh , okay .
That 's more like it .
[ SHIP HORN BLOWING ]
Here comes the next shift .
CARTER : I tell you , man
I quit this job .
Take me back to the ghetto .
Amen .
[ ENGLISH SDH ]